Yuri Bochkarev

Moscow (Russia) • baltazar.bz@gmail.com • +79853037426 • linkedin • github

Summary

Linux Python backend developer with 10+ years of experience in building, testing and maintaining complex software systems. 6+ years of Python experience, 6+ years of C++ experience, low-level background. Driven to get things done as well as to learn new skills, tools and technologies. Skilled to write efficient, maintainable and testable code.

Experience

IPONWEB – media trading platform (RTB, Ad exchange, DSP, SSP)

Moscow

Senior Software Developer (Internal Tools, Bidswitch)

June 2017 – present

- · Transitioned the user management and access control subsystem across departments that allowed for faster and simpler workflow and operations (Python3.6, Django 1.11, Django Rest Framework 3.6, Gabbi HTTP testing suite)
- Integrated Third-Party APIs with the internal discrepancy monitoring service (Python3.6, PostgreSQL 9.6)
- · Added support for bulk operations to internal creative blocking service, which saved about 1 hour a day for client support team (Python3.6, PostgreSQL 9.6)
- Integrated Third-Party API with the internal creative approval service (Python3.5, asyncio, Cassandra 2.6)
- Optimized user group update microservice to reduce processing time by 3x (Python 3.4, pytest, pymongo, TokuMX)
- Developed a facade API service to the internal DB as a part of an integration with a client (Golang 1.8, Cassandra
- · Added metrics to the "logs to DB" loading tool, which provided better understanding and visibility of the tool's internal state (C++ 11, Cassandra 2.6)
- Software development process: Scrum, Kanban
- Technology stack: Docker, Kubenetes, Sentry, Jenkins, Artifactory, OBS, Graphite, Grafana, Kibana, Ubuntu, Alpine

Senior Software Developer (Technology)

- Extended the functionality of the campaign visualization and forecasting service (Python, Django, Numpy, Scipy,
- Integrated forecasting service functionality with the custom testing stands
- Software development process: Scrum + Kanban

Software Developer (Technology)

July 2014 - May 2016

- · Optimized network communication subsystem of the budget control server for advertising campaigns, which reduced total iteration time by 30% (Python, Twisted, Numpy, Pandas)
- Rolled out Continuous Integration infrastructure (Jenkins, Trial, pytest, custom testing stands)

Software Developer (R&D)

January 2013 – July 2014

September 2009 – January 2013

- · Refactored and developed the data delivery service, made it more modular, testable and robust (Python, BASH, Django)
- Added performance/time metrics to comply with the established SLA
- · Standardized data transfer configuration DSL that is used across the company services
- Optimized file transfer time by integrating UDP-based file transfer solutions (UDT)

SmartLabs – interactive digital television (IPTV, DVB, OTT TV)

Moscow

System Department Developer

- Developed an RTSP request redirector (C++, Qt)
- Developed a video content distribution and publishing automation tool (C++, Qt)
- Integrated a third-party encryption service with the video content distribution automation tool (VeriMatrix)
- Improved SmartMedia platform video server seek time by implementing a faster file segment lookup algorithm (C++, Qt, STL, live555)
- Implemented an adaptive streaming client that was used in Set-Top Boxes (C++, Qt, Apple HTTP Streaming)
- Developed an interactive build automation tool that helped developers save time and do less mistakes when building platform components (Python)
- Took part in the implementation of the adaptive streaming server (Python, Twisted)
- Accompanying protocols: HTTP, XML RPC, SOAP, RTSP, HLS

Autoscan **Software Developer**

Ulvanovsk

September 2007 – May 2009

Prototyped and developed network applications for real-time video transmission (C++, Qt, OPAL, libjingle)

- Application testing automation (AutoIt, Erlang)
- Accompanying protocols: XMPP, SIP, RTP, STUN

Ulyanovsk State Technical University

Ulvanovsk

Technician

- September 2006 September 2007 Computer class administration (11 computers, ASP Linux 9.0, Microsoft Windows 2003)
- Class video surveillance organization, technical support

Education

Ulyanovsk State Technical University	Ulyanovsk
Master's degree, Faculty of Information Systems & Technologies, diploma VMA 0105774	2007 – 2009
Bachelor's degree, Faculty of Information Systems & Technologies, diploma AVB 0512119	2003 – 2007

Additional Education

Information Technology Alliance		coursera.org	
Clojure Course	April 2013	Machine Learning: Classification	April 2016
udacity.com	•	Game Theory (HSE)	March 2016
Programming a Robotic Car	April 2012	Machine Learning: Regression	February 2016
Artificial Intelligence	December 2011	ML Foundations: A Case Study Approach	February 2016
<u> </u>	December 2011	Cloud Computing Applications	October 2015
coursera.org	0 . 1 . 2012	Image and Video Processing	March 2015
Computing for Data Analysis	October 2012	Algorithmic Thinking	November 2014
Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part I	April 2012	Cryptography, Part I	June 2014
Machine Learning	December 2011	Write Like Mozart	March 2014
		Discrete Optimization	August 2013
		Functional Programming Principles in Scala	December 2012

Skills

Technical OS: GNU/Linux (since 2009), Windows (2001 – 2009). Programming Languages: Python, C++. Moderately experienced as well in: Go, Haskell, Clojure, R, Scala, Erlang, Lua, AutoIt, Java, Octave, x86 assembler. VCS: hg, git, svn. Technologies: Unit Testing, Design Patterns, UML. Frameworks: Twisted, Pyramid, Django, Pandas, Scipy. **Language** Russian (*native*), English (*upper intermediate*).